Andrew Haven drew.haven@stanford.edu 408-982-5425

April 4, 2010

Mozilla Corporation Mountain View, CA

To whom it may concern:

I love to program. It is where I am most comfortable and at home. However, my early career found me largely doing web development, system administration, and IT support. It is time for me to change and I want that change to make a difference by contributing to to the Mozilla family of software full-time. I've been carrying around a Firefox laptop bag for four years now and I would like to have a part in making something instead of just evangelizing.

My vocational software development experience is spotty, but I have made up for that as best I can through hobby programming—such as developing my own gift registry web application and learning Haskell—and by pursuing a masters in computer science through Stanford's SCPD program. I do not plan to ever stop learning and experimenting with new technologies, and the web is the place to do that. It isn't going to stop changing any time soon and I plan to be there keeping pace, whether that's implementing HTML5 and CSS3, or integrating that new mail protocol we've all been waiting for (and you know we need one but Wave hasn't taken off).

I want to transition my career into software engineering and development so that I can create things that people directly find useful and change user experiences for the better. I can think of no better place to do that than the Mozilla foundation, where quality software meets a set community-oriented values. I look forward to working with talented programmers making excellent software, and I hope to hear from you soon.

Sincerely,

Andrew Haven

Andrew Haven

drew.hav en@gmail.com // 408-982-5425

EXPERIENCE

2006-present	Computer Analyst Stanford University
	 Independently supported a department consisting of ~50 users and many heterogeneous systems.
	 Designed and developed MVC web applications using for time tracking, scheduling, and presentation evaluation.
	 Wrote software for driving experiments using Matlab and C.
	 Setup, maintained, tested and monitored file and web servers for each lab.
	 Administered private network of about 30 systems with centralized logins, networked file systems, and centralized licencing.
	 Designed and implemented a multi-tier backup system.
2006	Web Developer Infospider
	 Developed CRM, CMS and flat websites for clients.
	• Assisted designers with SEO.
2005-2006	Freelance Web Developer
	 Worked directly with clients to determine project scope and specifications.
	• Designed and developed two e-commerce web sites for small businesses.
2005	Contract Cable Monkey Streamline Communications
	 Assisted with the setup and tear down of network infrastructure surrounding events at the San Jose Convention Center.
	 Provided help desk support to customers at the convention center.
EDUCATION	
2008-present	M.S. Computer Science (in progress) Stanford University through SCPD
	Focus on software theory GPA: 3.94
2001-2005	B.S. Applied Physics University of California, Santa Cruz
	Minor in mathematics Thesis on genetic algorithms for high dimensional optimization problems GPA: 3.61
SKILLS	
Dev elopment	C, C++, Haskell, PHP, Perl, Ruby, Javascript, SQL, SVN, Git
Web	Apache, MySQL, Ruby on Rails, Mongrel, HTML, CSS
Systems Administration	Operating Systems: Windows, Linux, Solaris Services: NIS, NFS, ZFS, Samba, CIFS/SMB, DNS, NAT, HTTP, TCP/IP